Yomogi
Nursery
There we go.
Oh no, did that one break too?
It'd be nice if we could buy new ones...
They'll be fine if I can just fix them.
It's not like they need to be new to work well.
How is college going?
How is? I mean...
You're going when you're supposed to, right? You're getting all your credits?
Of course.
That's good.
You're always working so hard here...
Morning, Kobato!
Good morni- Ahhh!
Kobato fell again!
You're so clumsy!
Are you all right, Kobato?
Seriously...
Why do you keep tripping when there's nothing to trip over?
Ow...
Oh! Thank you...
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday, your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...A Kind Person.
Fujimoto!
I'll help you! Please let me help out!
Do as you like.
Okay!
Hey... Fujimoto?
There's something I wanted to ask you...
Fujimoto?
Be quiet and keep painting. If you have time to talk, then you're not working hard enough.
Okay...
What is it.
Huh?
I'm asking you what it is you wanted to ask me.
Oh! I see.
Um, it's about the strange
telephone call from the other day.
Why can't we tell Miss Sayaka about it?
We just can't right now.
Why can't we?
If you can't keep quiet about it,
then you can just stop coming here.
If you tell her, it'll make things difficult for her. That's why.
Difficult? For Miss Sayaka?
Are you trying to help or trying to get in the way?
What's the matter, Kobato?
I made Fujimoto angry again!
You did?
Yes. I kept getting in the way of his work.
It'll be fine if you just apologize to him, Kobato.
We'll come with you!
N               O
Wet paint,
don't touch!
I'm sure he only got angry because he was worried about you, Kobato.
Really?
Really! Don't be sad!
Mama always tells me, I want you to grow up well, that's why I get angry with you!
I see!
I'll apologize to him then ask him if he'll let me help out again!
Huh?
He's not here.
I wonder what this is.
This? It must be Fujimoto's report.
Report?
I wonder if he needs it today...
Kobato, do you mind delivering it to him?
Me?
I'm sure he's looking for it.
I'll bring it to him!
What's up. You're awfully excited.
I can't always be getting in the
way, I need to try and be helpful!
Fujimoto's college... is this way, right?
You did get directions before leaving, didn't you?
Yes! But what's "college"?
You came all this way
without even knowing that?!
Well, I can't say your lack of common sense really surprises me anymore.
College is a place where you study all sorts of difficult things.
Study?
When there's something you want to do,
or some job you're looking to get, y'know?
Something you want to do...
There are... There are so many people!
Well, it's a college. Makes sense that it would have this many people.
I wonder how many times bigger it is compared to Yomogi Nursery...
They're not comparable!!
Hurry up and go find him!
Okay, Ioryogi!
Student Cafeteria
Excuse me...
Excuse me?
One two, one two!
Excuse me!
Excuse... me?
Don't get lost!
I couldn't find him...
You just wandered aimlessly around campus!
I'll keep trying!
It's Fujimoto!
Why are you just standing there?
That's right, I need to deliver this!
Hey, don't trip now!
Sorry! Are you all right?
Yes...
I'm sorry!
Don't worry about it, I'm fine.
What a cute stuffed animal. Here you go.
Thank you.
And this is...
Are you... Kiyokazu's friend?
No! I mean... I'm not really his friend.
Something close to a friend then?
Yes! Probably...
Me too.
You are?
I'm Takashi Domoto. And you?
I'm Kobato Hanato! It's nice to meet you!
I came to bring that to Fujimoto.
Fujimoto!
He was just here...
Looks like he ran away.
You see, I kind of made him angry earlier.
Angry again?
Again?
Fujimoto gets angry very easily.
But! That's because I keep messing up...
But! I think he gets angry a little too often...
But... it's always because of
me, it's not Fujimoto's fault...
I see! Yomogi Nursery, huh?
Yes! I'm helping out there.
All right, let's go find Kiyokazu together, Kobato.
Find Fujimoto together? Is that okay?
Would I be in the way?
No, no, not at all! That would help me out a lot!
Great.
Around this time... he's probably in Jurisprudence.
Don't worry, I think he's
around campus all day today.
He should be cutting back on part-time hours.
Really?
It's almost exam time after all.
Fujimoto's always so busy.
He is, isn't he?
He takes so many classes, but still puts work first.
But that's just like Kiyokazu.
Domoto! Do us a favor!
What's up?
We were wondering if you could help us.
We have no idea where to start from on Professor Hayakawa's report.
Doesn't it suck that it's due next week?
I got it, I got it. I'll help.
Yay!
Thank you, Domoto!
Just to let you know, I'll help, but you'll be doing the work.
We know!
Thanks!
Man...
Well, let's go.
Fujimoto? Haven't seen him.
Maybe he's in the library?
Thanks.
If you do see him, can you tell him that I'm looking for him?
No can do!
That guy just doesn't get along with people. He's kinda scary.
That's not true.
Anyway, sorry.
Is everyone afraid of Fujimoto?
Well, he's not too friendly, and he always looks like he's angry about something.
Do you think he's scary too?
You said before that you made him angry...
Kiyokazu has reason to be angry.
He's always been the type who doesn't take help from anyone,
but I tried to give him advice about the future.
I've always known that he was like that, but I still opened my mouth.
How come?
I guess it was because I just couldn't leave him alone.
Miss Sayaka!
What's the matter?
Everyone's waiting! Hurry up and come play.
I'm sorry. Neither Fujimoto nor Kobato
are here today, you guys must be bored.
Not really...
Wait just a bit longer, okay?
Miss Sayaka!
You have a visitor!
Hello!
It's Chiho and Chise!
Chitose... What's the matter?
You see...
We made macarons with Mom!
And we wanted to share them with everyone!
Yeah!
Thank you!
Yummy!
It's so crispy!
Sayaka, where are Kiyokazu and Kobato?
The two of them are off at college today.
Kobato too?
Fujimoto? He just left.
I see. Thank you. I'll look around.
Wait up, Domoto.
You're close with Professor Tomita, right?
If I can't get credit this year, I'm in trouble. Could you say something to him for me?
Have you spoken to him yourself?
Ah... It's kind of awkward...
If someone he likes, like you, could put in a good word for me first...
All right. I'll do it.
Really? I owe you!
Talk to the Professor yourself too, got it?
blank
Got it! See you later!
Everyone really counts on
Domoto, don't they, Ioryogi?
Kobato!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
No, it's fine!
Would you mind if we took a little detour?
It's fine!
Even if you put it like that, his grades are just...
He's really upset about the whole thing...
Please, Professor Tomita. If
there's anything you could do.
All right, fine. Since you're the one who's asking.
Thank you very much.
Thanks for waiting.
You're amazing.
Amazing?
At what?
To have so many people count on you, and to be able to help so many people.
I guess.
Definitely! I wish I could help everyone,
but I just can't seem to get the hang of it...
You're amazing!
I don't know if I should say thank you for that or not...
Oh no, it's nothing. Shall we go?
Oh, yes!
Rock, paper, scissor, shoot!
Ah, I lost!
Then Chiho's it! Come on everybody, let's go hide!
One... two...
I see! That's why she went to college.
She seemed very excited about it.
That's Kobato for you, no?
Sayaka, will you take a look at this?
Yukari.
Chise?
R-Right...?
I got you, Yukari!
Ah, you're Chiho!
This is something that might help you
out if you're thinking of getting a loan.
And this one's from an accountant friend of mine.
And this one-
I'm sorry, Chitose.
Sayaka, do you understand?
I'm not helping you out of pity.
I want to help protect the Yomogi
Nursery that me, Chiho, and Chise went to.
So you don't need to apologize.
Thank you.
Finally found him.
What?!
You guys cut class, didn't you? I don't like helping people who do that.
If you don't like helping people, why don't you just say so!
Fine, I don't. I refuse.
Fine! Forget it!
We shouldn't have asked
someone like him anyway!
What are you doing here?
You're so mean!
About what?
You didn't need to say that in a way that would make people angry, did you?
If I didn't, they'd just keep asking.
Those girls might've had a reason for skipping.
Doesn't matter. Your business, take care of yourself.
Here! You forgot this. I brought it for you.
Kobato-
I can't believe I said that...
Kobato.
Domoto!
I forgot to thank you for
helping me look for Fujimoto!
I'm sorry...
Sit, sit.
When did you meet Kiyokazu?
Um, spring of this year.
I see.
How come?
I just felt jealous.
Of you and Kiyokazu.
Fujimoto and... I?
I've known Kiyokazu for
much longer than you have,
but I still can't speak to him the way you just did.
I really offended him, didn't I?
I said such disrespectful things...
No, what you said was right.
It's just that I can't say the right thing.
I'm sorry. I'm asking for too much.
There are so many wonderful things about you!
Like how you're so nice.
I'm not nice.
Huh? But you listen to everyone's requests and help them out!
That's very nice of you.
Actually, that's because I'm bad at refusing.
If I really wanted to help them out, I should refuse like Kiyokazu does.
You guys cut class, didn't you? I don't like helping people who do that.
Kiyokazu's not afraid of people
hating him. He's a strong person.
The reason people are afraid to get close to him
is probably because they're
overpowered by his strength.
I'm jealous of his strength.
Jealous of... his strength?
Yeah.
I don't know Fujimoto very well,
but being feared makes you lonely.
Being hated is painful.
Everyone we met today looked so happy
when you said that you would help them.
But that's-
Domoto.
Is not wanting to be hated a bad thing?
Is wanting to be liked a bad thing?
Is it bad to try and help people?
Is it wrong to want to help people who are troubled?
I can't explain it very well, but you're a good person.
Thank you.
You're a strange girl, aren't you.
Ah! I said something strange, didn't I?
I always make Ioryogi angry
because I don't know anything.
Ioryogi?
Yes! Ioryogi's a stuffed animal, but he can speak!
Even though he can speak, you can't speak to him!
Is that stuffed animal Ioryogi?
Yes!
Domoto!
The girls from earlier!
Well then, I'm off.
Yes! Thank you very much!
You too. See you later.
See you!
Huh?! Why did the konpeito...
Because you acknowledged
that attractive guy's kindness.
Attractive guy? Domoto?
Was there anyone else?
But, but, just by acknowledging his
kindness, I gained another konpeito?
No matter what others think, everyone has things that they're worried about.
Really?
I guess attractive guys have
attractive guy worries as well.
By the way, Dobato.
About this afternoon...
Yes?
Why did you tell him about me?!
But I did just as you said and didn't talk to you, Ioryogi!
No one would believe that a stuffed animal can speak!!
I'm sorry!
Kobato! 30 points!
What! No!
What?
I said you were helpful.
Oh, Fujimoto. Still the same as always.
He's just awkward. That was him trying his hardest to thank you.
Thank... me?
Kobato! Mr. Kiyokazu's not angry anymore, right?
He's not scary. Mr. Kiyokazu's nice, see.
He's nice! When I lost the key to my house, he found it for me!
He made a bamboo-copter for me!
He gave me cicada shells!
He's not a bad kid.
Yomogi
Nursery
Fujimoto... He's such
a strange person.
Yomogi
Nursery
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...The Kitten's Lullaby.